columbia.com 2019-09-10

# Columbia Sportswear Privacy Policy | Columbia Sportswear

Last Updated: March 13, 2019

This privacy policy ("Policy") explains how your information is collected, used, and disclosed by Columbia Sportswear Company and its subsidiaries and affiliated companies, including Mountain Hardwear and Sorel ("Columbia" or "We"). Unless we otherwise indicate, this Policy applies to all information collected by Columbia from any source, including information collected through our online services and activities, including this Website and our mobile applications (collectively, "Sites"), and at retail locations. This Policy will not apply where we display or link to a different privacy policy.

### 1\. INFORMATION WE COLLECT

We collect information from you in various ways, including through information you provide to us directly, information we or other third parties automatically collect, and information we receive from third parties. This includes data that identifies you personally whether directly (e.g., your name) or indirectly (e.g., information about your online use).

### A. Information You Provide

We collect information you directly provide to us through our Sites, in our stores and through your other interactions with us. This may include when you use our Sites, register or create an online account with or through the Sites, purchase products or services, request information from us, sign up for newsletters or our email list, use our service, enter into sweepstakes or other promotions, fill out a survey, request customer support, or otherwise communicate with or contact us.

The information we collect from you generally falls into the following categories:

  * **Contact Details:** We collect your contact information, such as name, postal address, email address, telephone or mobile number, fax number, or other similar identifiers.
  * **Financial Data:** If you make a purchase from us, we collect a credit/debit card number and related financial information (such as CVV, expiration date, and billing address), depending on the form of payment you choose.
  * **Transaction Details:** We may collect details about your purchases or other transactions with us, including, but not limited to, your transaction or purchase history, transaction channel, or the general location of the store you visit.
  * **Account Information:** You may choose to register for an account to make a purchase or use certain services. We collect information from you regarding your account registration, such as an email and password.
  * **Marketing and Communications Data:** We collect data concerning your preferences in receiving marketing, other targeted information from us, and your contact preferences.
  * **Other Data about You:** We may collect other information about you based on your interactions with us or that you choose to provide to us. For example, if you submit a product review you have the option to provide photographs or other information about yourself. You also have the option of providing your gender and birth month and date when enrolling in our Greater Rewards program.

### B. Information We Automatically Collect

When you visit or interact with our Sites, we may use a variety of technologies such as cookies, web beacons, pixel tags, log files, or other technologies to automatically or passively collect certain information about your online activity. Please note that we automatically collect the following information about you:

  * **Computer or Device Information.** We may automatically collect your Internet Protocol (IP) address or other unique identifier or information from the computer, mobile device, tablet or other device you use to access the Sites, including but not limited to your operating system, browser type and language, and information about the location of your device.
  * **Usage Information.** We may collect information about your usage of and activity on our Sites, including the date and time you visit the Sites, the areas or pages of the Sites that you visit, the amount of time you spend viewing or using the Site, the number of times you return to the Site, items that are added to or remain in your virtual cart on the Site, other click-stream or site usage data, emails that you open, forward or click-through to our Site, and other sites that you may visit.

For information about your advertising choices and how to opt-out of location information collection, please see the “Your Information Choices and Opt-Outs” section below.

### C. Information Collected by Third Parties

Third parties may also collect information about you on our Sites through the use of technology. For example, third party analytics services may use cookies and web beacons to help us compile statistics about our Sites and visitors to our Sites. We receive assurances from those third party analytics services that they will not collect or access any information that directly identifies you on our Sites. Other third parties may also collect information about your online activities over time and across different websites when you visit our Site, for example, to display Columbia ads to you on third party websites and to deliver third party ads to our Sites and others as described below. We also may use third party service providers to support our Sites.

This Policy does not apply to, and we are not responsible for, cookies or clear gifs in third party ads, and we encourage you to check the privacy policies of advertisers and/or ad services to learn about their use of cookies and other technology.

### D. Information Collected From Other Sources

We may obtain information from other sources as follows:

  * From other trusted third-party sources to update or supplement the information that you provide or that we collect automatically. This includes, for example, information from public databases or data aggregators (which may include your demographic information, previous purchases, shopping habits, lifestyle preferences, or other information to validate or supplement the information we collect from or about you).
  * From our partners and service providers (including, for example, business partners, analytics vendors, advertising networks and search information providers).

We may use this information to help us maintain the accuracy of the information we collect, personalize your experience on the Sites, target our communications so that we can inform you of products, services or other offers that may be of interest to you, to measure ad quality and responses, and for internal business analysis or other business purposes.

### E. Combination of Information

We may combine the information we collect from and about you, including information you provide to us and information we automatically collect through our Sites, as well as information collected offline, across other computers or devices that you may use, and from third party sources.

### 2\. INFORMATION USE

### A. Use of Information by Columbia

We use information we collect for purposes described in this Policy or as disclosed to you in other ways including on our Sites, in our stores, or in connection with our services. For example, we may use your information to:

  * provide and deliver products and services;
  * provide information we think may be helpful to you in your pursuit of the Greater Outdoors;
  * send you information related to products and services, including confirmations, invoices, technical notices, updates, security alerts, and support and administrative messages;
  * communicate with you about new contests, promotions and rewards, upcoming events, and other news about products and services offered by Columbia and our selected partners;
  * operate and improve our Sites, services and products;
  * process and deliver contest entries and rewards;
  * manage and administer our community features and member programs and services;
  * respond to your comments and questions and provide customer service;
  * provide you with customized content, targeted offers, and advertising on the Site, via email, direct mail or across other websites, mobile applications, social media or online services you may use;
  * link or combine with other personal information we get from third parties, to help understand your needs and provide you with better service;
  * use your data in an anonymous, aggregated, or de-identified format for analytical, marketing, and demographic purposes; and 
  * provide you with other services or for other purposes as disclosed at the time you provide your information or otherwise with your consent.

### B. How We Use Your Information for Interest-Based Advertising 

We and others may use information collected using third-party cookies, clear gifs, web beacons, or other technologies on our Sites and in our emails to deliver Columbia-branded advertising displayed to you on the Sites, on other third-party websites, mobile apps, social media, or other online services and across the computers or devices you use. We and others also may use cookie information to know when you return to our website after visiting these third-party websites. We and others use this and other information about you to try to understand your interests and show you relevant advertising about products and services that may interest you.

We also may display interest-based ads through digital advertising partners, like Facebook, Google, or other social media platforms or websites. For example, we may use these digital advertising partners to personalize ads you see on other websites or apps based on your shopping experience with us. We do this only by sharing hashed information (which converts your email or phone number to a unique string of numbers and letters) that the social media platform then matches data against its own data for the limited purpose of serving advertisements (either directly to you or to other lookalike audiences). The matched and unmatched hashes are then deleted, and are not used for any other purpose.

We also may use information we collect to deliver advertising that is targeted to individuals with similar interests. These tools allow us to create groups based on actual or assumed shared interests and/or factual characteristics based on anonymous and/or de-identified information to help us figure out what advertising may be most relevant. We also do this without having to share personal information with these third-party partners.

For more information about this practice and your choices with respect to interest-based ads, see the “Your Information Choices” section below.

### 3\. SHARING OF INFORMATION

Certain sections of our Sites are designed as open and public community areas for connecting and sharing with other people. When you sign up for or participate in these areas you will be asked to provide certain information that may be displayed publicly along with photos, stories, posts, product reviews and other information you choose to provide. We may also post or publish your information when you submit comments, stories, photos, and videos in connection with surveys, contests, sweepstakes, or promotions offered on the Sites.

We share your personal information with third parties as follows:

  * with your consent, including if we notify you on the Sites that the information you provide will be shared in a particular manner and you provide such information or when you agree to our sharing of your information with other third parties for their own marketing purposes subject to their separate privacy policies;
  * with third party vendors, consultants and other service providers who are working on our behalf and need access to your information to carry out their work for us, including fulfilling orders or assisting us in advertising our products and services on third party websites;
  * if you choose to enter into one of our sweepstakes, contests, or other promotions (a “Promotion”) we may disclose your information to third parties or the public in connection with the administration of such Promotion, as required by law, as otherwise permitted by the Promotion’s official rules, or otherwise in accordance with the terms of this Policy;
  * to (a) comply with laws or respond to lawful requests and legal process, (b) to protect the rights and property of Columbia, our agents, and others, including to enforce our agreements, policies and terms of use or (c) in the good faith belief that disclosure is needed to respond to an emergency or protect the personal safety of any person; and
  * in connection with, or during negotiations of, any merger, sale of company assets, financing or acquisition of all or a portion of our business to another company.

### 4\. SECURITY OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

Columbia takes reasonable measures to protect your personal information in an effort to prevent loss, misuse and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration and destruction. While we make every effort to help ensure the integrity and security of our network and systems, we cannot guarantee our security measures.

### 5\. YOUR INFORMATION CHOICES AND OPT-OUTS

### A. Cookies, Tracking Options and California Do Not Track Disclosures

Certain parts of our Sites require cookies. You may adjust your device or Internet browser settings to limit certain tracking or to decline cookies, but by doing so, you may not be able to use certain features of the Service or take full advantage of all of our offerings. Please refer to your device’s settings or your Internet browser’s “Help” section for more information on how to delete and/or disable your device or browser from receiving cookies or controlling your tracking preferences.

While we and others give you choices described in this Policy, there are many ways Web browser signals and other similar mechanisms can indicate your choice to disable tracking. Our system may not recognize Do Not Track requests or headers from some or all browsers. We may use cookies or other technologies to deliver more relevant advertising and to link data collected across other computers or devices that you may use.

### B. Interest-Based Advertising Choices

To understand your choices for receiving more relevant advertising provided on the Sites or across other websites and online services, please review the information below:

  * To learn more about such interest-based advertising, and to opt out of such collection and use for interest-based advertising by the Digital Advertising Alliance (DAA) participating companies, please visit <http://www.aboutads.info/choices/>.
  * To opt out from the use of information about your online activities for interest-based advertising by Network Advertising Initiative (NAI) member companies, please visit <http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/>.
  * To opt-out of the use of your mobile device ID for targeted advertising, please see <http://www.aboutads.info/appchoices>.
  * On your mobile device, you may also adjust your privacy and advertising settings to control whether you want to receive more relevant advertising.

**Adobe Marketing Cloud** : We participate in the Adobe Marketing Cloud Device Cooperative to better understand how you use certain websites and apps of ours across the various devices you use, and to deliver tailored advertisements to you across those devices. To learn more information about this cross-device tracking or to unlink your device, visit: [https://cross-device-privacy.adobe.com](https://cross-device-privacy.adobe.com/).

### C. Unsubscribing from our Marketing Communications

You may opt out of receiving promotional emails from Columbia by clicking on the unsubscribe link at the bottom of those emails, or clicking the following link <https://www.columbia.com/on/demandware.store/Sites-Columbia_US-Site/en_US/Email-Unsubscribe> and entering the email address you wish to unsubscribe. If you choose to opt out of promotional emails, we may still send you non-promotional emails, such as emails about your accounts or our ongoing business relations.

You may also send requests about your contact preferences or changes to your information by writing us at:

  * Columbia Sportswear Company  
Attn: Ecommerce 14375 N.W. Science Park Dr.  
Portland, OR 97229

### D. Opting Out of Location Collection

You may opt out from allowing Columbia to collect your geographic location by changing your location preferences on your mobile device or by following the standard uninstall process and deleting Columbia's mobile application(s) from your device.

### 6\. DATA STORAGE

This website is operated by Columbia Sportswear Company, a company which is headquartered in the United States of America. To provide you with this website and the goods and services you order, your data may be processed by Columbia Sportswear Company, its group companies, and it service providers, who may be located in countries (including the USA) other than your country of residence. These countries may have data protection laws that are different than the laws in your country of residence, but Columbia Sportswear Company will protect your personal information in accordance with applicable data protection law and this Policy at all times.

### 7\. YOUR CALIFORNIA PRIVACY RIGHTS

If you are a California resident, you may request information about our disclosure of personal information to third parties or affiliated companies for their direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please contact us at [privacy@columbia.com](mailto:privacy@columbia.com). You must put the statement “Your California Privacy Rights” in the subject field. We are not responsible for notices that are not labeled or sent properly, or do not have complete information.

Non-affiliated third parties are independent from Columbia and if you wish to receive information about your disclosure choices or stop communications from such third parties, you will need to contact those non-affiliated third parties directly.

### 8\. THIRD-PARTY CONTENT, LINKS, AND PLUG-INS 

The Sites may have links to third-party websites, which may have privacy policies that differ from our own. We are not responsible for the practices of such sites.

The Sites may also offer you the ability to interact with social plugins from social media sites, which may allow us and/or the social media site to receive data from or about you. In some cases, we may know that you clicked on a social plugin, such as a Twitter Follow button, or receive other information from the social media sites. Similarly, if you have previously provided personal information to a third-party operating a plug-in on this Site, then such third-party may recognize you on this Site. Your use of social network plugins is subject to each social media site’s privacy policy, which may be different from ours, so please read these policies carefully to understand their policies and your options. As with linked sites, we have no control over the information that is collected, stored, or used by social network plugins, and are not responsible for the practices of such sites.

### 9\. CHILDREN’S PRIVACY

Protecting children’s privacy is important to us. We do not direct the Sites to, nor do we knowingly collect any personal information from, children under the age of thirteen. If Columbia learns that a child under the age of thirteen has provided personally identifiable information to the Sites, we will use reasonable efforts to remove such information from our files.

### 10\. CHANGES TO THIS POLICY

Columbia may change this Policy from time to time. If we make any changes to this Policy, we will change the "Last Updated" date above.

### 11\. QUESTIONS/CONTACT US

If you have any questions about this Policy or our privacy practices, you may email us at [privacy@columbia.com](mailto:privacy@columbia.com).
